

PARVATHY VAZHOOR WEB DEVELOPER

- parvathyvd@gmail.com
 - **3** 604-358-3962
- in linkedin.com/in/parvathy-vazhoor
 - ♦ codepen.io/parvathyvd
 - github.com/parvathyvd

PORTFOLIO

realwordpressdevelopment.com/webfolio

EDUCATION

Bachelors Degree in Computer Science

Vidya Academy of Science & Technology, India

LANGUAGES

English

Hindi

OTHER INTERESTS

Biking

Glass Painting

Dancing

CONTACT ADDRESS

8277 161st Surrey BC, V4N0N3

CAREER PROFILE

I am a web developer specializing in Front end development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PHP(Codeigniter) and Vanila Javascript(Jquery,React). Strong background in Wordpress web development and design.

WORK HISTORY

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER (FREELANCER)

REALWORDPRESSDEVELOPMENT (09/2020 to Present)

Developed web apps using HTML5, CSS3, BOOTSTRAP and Javascript(React).

Developed custom websites using Wordpress CMS.

Developed custom themes, Set up the stripe payment checkout using glass register for charity websites.

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

RSTINSTRUMENTS (09/2018 Sep to 09/2020)

Responsible for redeveloping the RST website.

Upgraded the HTML website to custom **PHP** website and **MYSQL** database with newer design. Designed and developed website using PHP, HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript ES6.

Migrated and redeveloped the entire website with same design in to the **Wordpress**.

WEB DEVELOPER/DESIGNER

BRIKERS (05/2017 to 07/2018)

Developed Brikers website wireframe using Lucidchart.

Developed brikers website using Codeigniter(PHP framework), Bootstrap and jquery. Used SASS preprocessor.

Tested webpage for responsiveness and adjusted the media queries accordingly.

WEB DEVELOPER/DESIGNER

ENGAGEMEDIA (07/2013 to 04/2017)

Responsible for all stages of Web site creations for client, from initial design and architecture to development, deployment, and management.

Developed websites mainly **Wordpress CMS**. Responsible for Domain registration, Webhosting, Wordpress, theme, plugin installation and customization.

Developed custom wordpress templates

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

ABSOLUTE NATURAL PRODUCTS (Freelance 09/2016 to 10/2016)

Responsible for all stages of Web site development. Wordpress Web design/development, Social Media, SEO, Business Card design and Office 365 email configuration. Hosted the domain and installed the WordPress CMS. Added necessary plugins and Customized the website.

WEB DEVELOPER

BUSINESS ASSIST CANADA(Freelance 06/2014 to 11/2014)

Responsible for all stages of Web site development. Web design/development, Social Media, SEO, Graphic Card design and Office 365 email configuration.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3 (SASS,SCSS) Bootstrap Javascript ES6 & Jquery WordPress PHP7, Codeigniter React Npm, Webpack & Babel **MYSQL** Lucidchart, Asana Photoshop, Illustrator Git & Github & Terminal Email Marketing & SEO Google Search Console Google Tag Manager Godaddy & Hostgator Mailchimp Filezila VSC, Phpstorm, Atom, Coda2, Dreamweaver **MAMP**